# **Sergey Kambalin**

Senior Software Developer

kambalin@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sergeykambalin

Professional software developer with 10+ years of experience in TypeScript, JavaScript and PHP development. Always trying to keep abreast of technology trends and best programming practices. Productive in both team-based and self-managed projects.

## **Technical Skills**

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, GraphQL

**Frameworks** React, React Native, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, GraphQL-PHP, Express **Tools** Webpack, Babel, Storybook, Lerna, NPM, Yarn, Composer, Docker

Tests Jest, Enzyme, Testing Library

# **Professional Experience**

## **Evolution Gaming**

Senior Software Developer Nov 2019 - present

- Migrated a complex legacy project from JavaScript/AngularJS to TypeScript/React with unit testing on Jest
- Refactored the legacy project from monolithic to modular structure
- · Participate in interviewing and mentoring programs

Technology stack:

- · TypeScript, JavaScript
- React & Redux ecosystem
- Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Lerna + Yarn Workspaces
- Jest, Enzyme, React/DOM Testing Library

#### **IOLA**

Senior Software Developer/Architect

Oct 2018 - Nov 2019

- Designed, developed and successfully delivered React Native iOS and Android application
- Designed and developed modular GraphQL server on PHP
- · Developed UI kit based on Web Components

Technology stack:

- · React, React Native, GraphQL, Web Components
- Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Lerna
- · SlimPHP, GraphQL-PHP

## Klika Tech LLC

Senior Software Developer/Team Lead

Oct 2016 - Sep 2018

- Took part in various company projects as a full stack JavaScript/PHP developer
- Led a team developing JavaScript SDK for a customer which is used across many projects
- · Participated in interviewing and mentoring programs
- · Was the company's frontend community leader

Technology stack:

- · React, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Mocha, Chai, Sinon
- · PHP, PHPUnit, NodeJs, Sails, Express

## Skalfa Asia LLC

Senior Software Developer/Team Lead

Dec 2012 - Sep 2016

- · Led design and development of a hybrid IOS/Android application based on Ionic Framework and SlimPHP
- Was a lead developer in a team designing and developing open source website platforms: Oxwall, Skadate
- · Led development of native iOS application for online dating platform: Skadate

Software Developer

Jul 2010 - Dec 2012

• Took part in the development of a high load SaaS solution: Wall.fm

Junior Software Developer

Mar 2009 - Jul 2010

Developed various modules for online dating platform: Skadate

#### **Education**

## **International University of Kyrgyzstan**

Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Bachelor of Information Technology, Software Engineer

Sep 2003 - Jun 2007